export const quizList = [
    {
        "question":"What is React?",
        "choice1":"A backend framework",
        "choice2":"A programming language",
        "choice3":"A frontend JavaScript library",
        "choice4":"A database management system",
        "answer":"A frontend JavaScript library",
        "no":1
    },
    {
        "question":"Which component lifecycle method is invoked after a component is rendered for the first time?",
        "choice1":"componentDidMount()",
        "choice2":"componentDidUpdate()",
        "choice3":"componentWillMount()",
        "choice4":"componentWillUnmount()",
        "answer":"componentDidMount()",
        "no":2
    },
    {
        "question":"What does JSX stand for in React?",
        "choice1":"JavaScript XML",
        "choice2":"JSON XML",
        "choice3":"JavaScript Extension",
        "choice4":"JSX doesn't stand for anything",
        "answer":"JavaScript XML",
        "no":3
    },
    {
        "question":"What is the purpose of state in React?",
        "choice1":"To store component methods",
        "choice2":"To manage and maintain a component's internal data",
        "choice3":"To render HTML elements",
        "choice4":"To define CSS styles",
        "answer":"To manage and maintain a component's internal data",
        "no":4
    },
    {
        "question":"What function is used to render a React component?",
        "choice1":"renderComponent()",
        "choice2":"createComponent()",
        "choice3":"displayComponent()",
        "choice4":"render()",
        "answer":"render()",
        "no":5
    },
    {
        "question":"Which of the following is used to pass data from a parent component to a child component in React?",
        "choice1":"setState()",
        "choice2":"this.props",
        "choice3":"this.state",
        "choice4":"getDerivedStateFromProps()",
        "answer":"this.props",
        "no":6
    },
    {
        "question":"What is the purpose of keys in React lists?",
        "choice1":"To add styling to list elements",
        "choice2":"To uniquely identify elements in an array",
        "choice3":"To define the order of elements in a list",
        "choice4":"To create nested lists",
        "answer":"To uniquely identify elements in an array",
        "no":7
    },
    {
        "question":"What is the React method used for handling component errors?",
        "choice1":"componentDidCatch()",
        "choice2":"catchComponentError()",
        "choice3":"errorHandling()",
        "choice4":"handleComponentError()",
        "answer":"componentDidCatch()",
        "no":8
    },
    {
        "question":"Which method is used to prevent unnecessary re-renders in React?",
        "choice1":"shouldComponentUpdate()",
        "choice2":"componentDidUpdate()",
        "choice3":"componentWillUpdate()",
        "choice4":"getSnapshotBeforeUpdate()",
        "answer":"shouldComponentUpdate()",
        "no":9
    },
    {
        "question":"What is the tool recommended by React for maintaining state management in large applications?",
        "choice1":"Redux",
        "choice2":"React Router",
        "choice3":"Axios",
        "choice4":"ESLint",
        "answer":"Redux",
        "no":10
    }
]
